DHR&Hakugetsu Sub
翻譯：因果律 モビイ·ディック 大湿 時間軸：KoU 後期：水姬 壓制：沙夏 KoU
I have to do something.
何とかしないと…
ばぶ…
I have to preserve Rea's body.
俺が　礼弥の体を守らないと
ウ～ビィ…
Nemurenai yoru ni kiita monogatari ga
What if the story I heard that sleepless night
esoragoto da to shitara
was all just an impossible dream?
Eien wo shiru yori kairaku wo motomete
What if I pursue pleasure, and lament the moment
ima wo kuyande shimau no wa
instead of learning about the eternities
kokoro no fukaku ni sumitsuita kage kara
so that I can escape from the shadows
nigeru tame da to shitara
that dwell deep within my heart?
Sore demo atashi wa atashi wa ai shite irareru nara
But even so, as long as I, as long as I can still keep loving
Hanbun ni wareta taiyou ga asa wo tsurete kite
The sun split in half brings with it the morning
yami ni nareta shinkei wo jiwari shigeki suru
gradually stimulating my nerves, so used to the darkness
Okiwasureta ano ai wa aete sono mama de
I'll dare to leave the love that I'd misplaced as it is
Shinario no kieta monogatari wa
A story whose plot has been erased,
jiyuu ni jiyuu ni kaji wo totte
freely, freely, takes the helm,
motto takaku e maiagatte
soaring ever higher
"If She`s a Zombie... That Means... "
Good night.
おやすみ
Rea's body is going through rigor mortis.
死後硬直を起こしている
礼弥の体…
The way it's going,
her body will gradually decay away.
このままだと
徐々に肉体が腐っていってしまう
First thing I need to do,
before the rigidity goes away,
とりあえず　硬直が解けるまでに
何とか
is find some way of maintaining Rea's body.
礼弥の体を維持する方法を
見つけないと
"Namu Amida Buddha"
"Furuya Mero, Class 4-2"
A book on preserving a body?
遺体の保存方法の本？
Yes. I know you read one once before.
I need you to lend it to me.
そう
お前　確か　前に読んでただろ？
あれ　貸してほしいんだけど
ああ…
Ah, that book that dealt with embalming?
エンバーミングに関する書籍のことか？
I lent it out to a classmate.
あれは　級友に貸したままだが…
A classmate? What kind
of middle-schooler is this?
級友って　どんな中学生だよ？
One between a grade-schooler
and a high-schooler.
小学生の上で　高校生の下
いや　それは知ってるけど…
にーこそ
Yeah, that much I get.
Brother, what do you need such a book for?
何故　そのような本を？
あッ？
Oh, nothing...
ああ…　いや…
If you don't have it, never mind.
ないなら　いいんだ
Bye.
じゃあな
最近　変であるな…
He's been weird lately, huh?
I guess the easiest thing
to do would be formalin.
やっぱ　一番多いのは
ホルマリンなのか？
But apparently, the smell is awful.
でも　臭いが　すごいらしいし
Ask before
coming in!!!
I have to keep the family and
the neighbors from finding out.
家族や近所に
バレないようにしないと
Looking at her like this,
エアコンがかかっている
こうやって見てると
普通に寝てるだけみたいだよな
she looks like she's just sleeping normally.
Hey, Chihiro and Mero!
Get up already!
おーい　千紘　萌路
早う起きてこんか
A-All right!
あッ　分かったよ！
I can't just leave her on the bed, huh?
やっぱベッドじゃ　まずいよなあ
I could move her into the closet.
押し入れに移すか
There.
よし！
You know, I'm not sure where I should be looking.
にしても　目のやり場に困るなあ
イッテエ…
Chihiro, what's the matter?
千紘　どうしたんだ？
Aw, man...
あーッ　もう…
I'll be right there!
すぐ行くって！
うん…
たぶん　今日の夜までに
硬直　解けるだろうから
The stiffness should probably
go away by this evening.
I'm sorry this is so cramped,
but just lie still in here for now. Okay?
狭くて悪いけど
ここで　じっとしててくれ
いいな？
W-What was that sound? Her stomach?
おなか？
Are you hungry, by any chance?
ひょっとして　お前…
腹へってんのか？
Well, once you can move again,
I'll get you something to eat.
じゃあ　動けるようになったら
何か食べさせてやるからな
父ちゃーん　今行くー
Daddy, I'm coming!
Thank you for this meal.
いただきます
- Thank you for this meal.
Our usual breakfast...
いつもの朝食
おいッ　味噌汁の具に
かまぼこは　やめんか
Hey, could you not put
fish paste in the miso soup?
Dad, that's tofu.
父さん　それは　豆腐だよ
あんッ
The scene at my house is the
same normal setting that it always is.
俺んちの　いつもながらの
普通の風景だ
Please let me have all of the experiences
普通の女の子として
すべての経験をさせてください
that a normal girl should have.
なあ　普通って何なんだろうな？
Say, what is "normal," anyway?
だしぬけに何を言う？
That's a question from out of the blue.
Nah, never mind.
いや　何でもねえ
Hey, could you not put
fish paste in the miso soup?
おいッ　味噌汁の具に
かまぼこは　やめんか
Dad, that's tofu.
父さん　それは豆腐だよ
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました
ふ～ん　礼弥さんが…
Hmm... So Rea is...
ぷはーッ
うわッ！
あッ　なーんだ
蘭子先輩じゃないですか
Oh, if it isn't you, Ranko!
Gee, it's you again?
もう　またアンタか
What are you up to around here?
どうしたんですか？　こんな所で
The family business.
ウチの仕事
つか　アンタこそ
ここで何してんの？
And for that matter,
what are you doing here?
Oh, well you see...
いや　それがですね
クラスメートの礼弥様が
Miss Rea, one of my classmates,
wasn't in school today.
学校を休んでおりましてん
So I got worried about her,
and came to see how she was.
それでもう心配になって
様子を見に来たんですよ
Is that right? But then, you could
have gone on in normally, right?
そうなんだ…
てか　普通に入ったらいいじゃん
え～ッ？
にしても　暇なんだねえ
And I have to say,
you've got too much free time.
Well... Miss Rea is our class idol, after all.
だって
礼弥様は　ウチらのアイドルですよ
Of course, you're just
as much of an idol to us, Ranko.
もちろん　ウチにとっては
蘭子先輩も同じくらい
アイドルですけど
Never mind about all that.
そういうの　いいって
Miss Rea hasn't been herself somehow lately.
何だか　最近の礼弥様
少し様子が変だったんです
I mean, she's still the
great girl she's always been,
いや　素敵なのは
変わらないんですけど
but there's something
sad about her somehow.
どこか　悲しそうっていうか…
へえ～
And it's an unexcused absence, at that.
しかも　無断欠席ですよ
もう　気になって気になって
I just can't stop thinking about it.
Oh, yeah?
あっそ
Well, Ranko, from your standpoint,
she is your underclassman,
まあ　蘭子先輩からすれば
やっぱ　後輩だし
それほど興味ないかもですけど
so you might not
be that interested in this,
but for us first-years,
ウチら１年生で　礼弥様に
興味ない人はいませんよ
there isn't anyone who
isn't interested in Miss Rea.
She really is that great.
ホント　素敵なんですから
Ah, look at these pictures!
あッ　写真　見てくださいよ
Let's see, there are many
different versions here...
えっとですね
色々なバージョンがあるんですけどね
Okay, let's start with
the shot that I think is the best.
じゃあ　まずは
ウチが一番素敵だと思うショットから
How's that? She looks alluringly
gentle and noble here, doesn't she?
どうです？　穏やかで高貴な感じに
ウットリしちゃいますでしょ？
And here's a three-shot of us.
で　これがスリーショット
Next up is my prized two-shot!
次が大事なツーショット
ふ～ん
でも　礼弥様のお宅
But the maids at Miss Rea's house
were in a fairly big uproar, huh?
何かメイドさん達が
やたらバタバタしてましたね
I wonder what exactly could be going on.
一体　何があったんでしょうね？
Yeah, there was a real commotion inside.
ああ　中　すっごい騒いでたね
What could the matter be?
どうしちゃったんでしょう
ひょっとしたら
You don't suppose something could
have happened to Miss Rea, do you?
礼弥様の身に何かあったんかも
Wait, Ranko!
て　蘭子先輩！
Geez...
もう…
Today is a day off! No school today!
今日は休日
学校は休み
家族総出で…
寺の掃除
The whole family is working
together to clean the temple.
Damn, I don't have time
to be doing this right now.
クッソ～　今は　こんなことしてる
場合じゃないのに
Chihiro, I hear you're thinking
of keeping another cat, aren't you?
千紘
お前　また猫を飼おうと
しているそうじゃないか
Babu has just barely
passed away. What's the idea?
こないだ　ばーぶを亡くしたばかり
なのに　どういうことだ？
It's not like that, Daddy.
Babu has come back to life.
違うって　父ちゃん　ばーぶは
生き返ったんだっての
What kind of nonsense is that?
何を分からんことを…
Hey, Grandpa, you saw him, right? Babu?
なあ　じいちゃんも見たろ？
ばーぶを
That's right. It was Babu.
そうじゃ　あれは　ばぶーじゃった
You see? Even Grandpa says so.
ほーら
じいちゃんも　そう言ってる
That's right, that's right!
そうじゃそうじゃ
Sada and Baboo have both come back to life!
貞も　ばぶーも
よみがえりよったんじゃ
Yeah, yeah, Sada and Baboo have...
そうそう　貞も　ばぶーも…
貞って誰だよ？
つか　「ばーぶ」だっての！
Who's Sada?
And it's "Babu"!
Good grief, they've both gone dotty.
まったく　二人ともボケて…
うん
Mm-hmm...
The reanimation pill that I made
わしの作った蘇生丸は
もっと世に評価されるべきじゃ
deserves more recognition
throughout the world.
Yeah, yeah, the reanimation pi...
そうそう　蘇生丸…
Huh?
えッ？　じ…　じいちゃん！
G-Grandpa, what did you just say?
今　何て言った？
Huh? Sada?
えッ？　貞か？
違う！
No, after that, after that!
その後　その後
えッ？
Reanimation pill? You don't, by
any chance, mean that drug, do you?
蘇生丸って　ひょっとして
あの薬のこと言ってんのか？
Not to mention, "...that I made..."
しかも　「わしが作った」って…
うッ…
そんなこと言ったっけ？
Did I say that?
Yes, you did.
言ったよ
知らん　そんなもん
Don't know nothing about it.
I'm gonna go take a bath.
風呂入ってくる
ちょッ　ちょっと…
H-Hold on...!
うぐッ…
こら　まだ掃除が終わっとらんだろ
Hey, you're not done cleaning yet, right?
You always try to run away.
いつも　すぐ逃げようとしおって
You should be ashamed, Brother.
みっともないのう　にーよ
にゃ～
Yeah...
ミャオ～　ガオ～
Hey, come on, now...
If Grandpa really was
the one who created that drug...
もしホントに　あの薬を
じいちゃんが作ったんだとしたら
Yeah, knowing Grandpa,
he's more than capable of it.
いや　あのじいちゃんなら
十分ありうるぞ
If true, maybe he knows some kind of method
だとしたら　蘇生後の
肉体の維持の方法についても
for preserving reanimated flesh.
何か知ってるんじゃ…
Brother...
にーよ
おッ！
What do you want?!
何だよ？　いきなり
Brother, I'll bet your room
hasn't been cleaned, as usual.
相変わらず　にーの部屋は
掃除が　されていないのであろうな
ハックション！
後ほど　にーの部屋も
I'll go up and clean your room later, Brother.
掃除しておくぞ
ああ　悪いな
Yeah, thanks.
うん？
いや　萌路　ちょっと…
I mean, Mero, hold on!
うん？
俺の部屋さ
About my room...
you don't have to clean it today.
今日は　掃除　いいから
何故　そのような？
Why would you say such a thing?
Oh, well... What can I say?
何つーか　最近　俺　掃除に
目覚めちゃったらしいんだわ
Lately, I seem to have come around to cleaning.
No fooling. So, never mind
about cleaning and stuff.
いや　マジ
だから　掃除とか　大丈夫だから
ヘッ…　ホント　マジで…
ハハハハハ…
Really. No fooling.
ハハハハハハ…
あい　分かった
Okay, you got it.
アッハハハハハ…
Incomprehensible...
げせぬのう…
We appreciate your patronage!
毎度　おおきに～
あッ？
わんこ
Wanko!
Oh, it's Ranko.
おう　蘭子ちゃんか
What are you here for, Wanko?
This is two days in a row.
何だよ　わんこ　連日来て
I was just stopping by
on my way back from a delivery.
仕出し　届けたついでに
寄ったんです～
Here you go, Mero. Have some lunch.
はい　萌路ちゃん
お昼に　ど～ぞ
Thank you much, Lady Wanko.
おおきに　わんこどの
We always appreciate you doing this.
いやあ　いつも助かるよ
やっぱ　あれだなあ
It's like, you know...
This one is entirely self-centered, right?
まったく　こやつは自己中だろ
蘭子ちゃんみたいな子が
He has to have someone like you around, Ranko
姉さん女房として
いてやらんと　いかんかなあ
to play the older wife figure for him.
Gee whiz, wife, you say?! Oh, Uncle!
女房だなんて　もうッ！
おじさまったら～　アッハッハ…
なッ…
あッ　そうだそうだ
Ah, oh yeah...
Chihiro, have you heard?
千紘さ　知ってる？
うん？　何をだよ？
Huh? Heard what?
That girl from the Sanka family
散華家のお嬢様
supposedly ran away from home yesterday.
昨日から　家出してるらしいよ
うん？
あッ…　いや…
Oh... no.
Yeah, and the Sanka family
are regular customers of ours.
でね　散華家は　ウチの店の
お得意様なんだけど
When I was making a delivery
there earlier, there was a big to-do.
さっき　仕出し　渡しに行ったら
大騒ぎになっててさ
I guess even girls like
her have their problems, huh?
あんな子でも
悩みとかあるんだね…
O-Oh...
It could be...
ひょっとして
死に別れた恋人と再会して
...that bereaved, she reunited
with her lover, tasted forbidden love,
禁断の恋をしてしまい
駆け落ちしちゃったのかもー！
and the two of them wound up eloping!
Bereaved? Who's dead?
死に別れって…　死んでんじゃん
And the two of them spent the night together,
そして二人は　海の見える
小さな民宿で　一夜を共にするの
in a small guest room, with a view of the sea.
They were destined to never be bound together.
結ばれてはいけない運命の二人
But unaware of this,
they strove to grow closer, body and soul.
でも　それを知らない彼らは
身も心も　より結びつこうと…
で　やっぱ　千紘も　ああいう子が
タイプなんだ？
But then, Chihiro,
that kind of girl is your type, right?
Huh?
あれ～？　だって
アンタの変な友達も言ってたじゃん
After all, that weird friend of yours did say
that you and that Rea girl
were pretty close, didn't he?
千紘と　あの礼弥って子が
親しいってさ
No, like I said,
いや　だから　あれは…
I just ran into her when
I happened to be out one night.
たまたま夜に外出してたときに
ばったり会って
All we did was engage in a little chit-chat.
ちょっくら雑談のようなものを
交わしただけで
ふ～ん
つーか
And how come you
would bring something like that up?
何で　お前に　そんなこと
話さなきゃいけないんだよ
Ah, well, you see, as your older sister,
え～ッ　そりゃあさ
やっぱ姉として
I need to know the kind
of company my brother keeps.
弟の交友関係は
知っておかなくちゃ
But I'm telling you, it's not like that.
だから　べつに
そういうあれじゃねえって
Okay, gotcha.
そッ　分かった
Well, I've got to help
out at home, so I'm leaving.
じゃあ　私　家の手伝いあるから
帰るわ　お邪魔しましたー
Pardon the intrusion!
What's with her?
What's she trying to say?
何だよ　アイツ
何が言いたいんだよ？
Hey, Chihiro, hurry up and
scrub down out back, would you?
おい　千紘！　さっさと
裏手の方も　雑巾がけせんか
I know!
分かってるって！
Oh, yeah, as long as I've stopped by,
I'll borrow a zombie DVD.
そうだ　せっかく立ち寄ったんだし
ゾンビＤＶＤ　借りてこう
There's a big fuss at Rea's house, huh?
礼弥んち
大騒ぎになってるのか…
I suppose there would be.
Her dad seems really intimidating.
そうだよなあ　あの父ちゃん
おっかなそうだったよなあ
でも
今のままで　帰すわけには…
But I can't send her back
there the way things are now.
May I come in?
お邪魔しまーす
Whoo, it's cold! What's going on?
うん？　うッ　さぶッ！
何これ？
この時期に　エアコンかけてんの？
He's running the air conditioner,
at this time of day?
Hmm, let's see,
which ones haven't I borrowed yet?
うーんと　どれが
まだ借りてないやつだっけ？
The names of these zombie
movies all sound alike.
ゾンビ映画って
似たような名前ばっかだなあ
Ah, geez... Ugh,
this one's in the wrong case!
あ～もう…
げッ　これ　中身違うじゃん！
ばーぶー
あッ…
Which... one... of... these..
should... I... se... lect...?
ど・れ・に・し・よ・う・か・な
I... will... ask... God... and...
he... will... pick... this... one.
神様の・い・う・と・お・り
Oh, I just watched that one not long ago.
うわッ
これ　こないだ見たやつだし
A long black hair?
長い黒髪
There's no way this could be Chihiro's, right?
これ　どう考えても
千紘のじゃないよね
Wait...
はあ…　気のせいか
Must be imagining things.
Come to think of it,
Rea seemed like she was hungry earlier.
そういやあ　さっき　礼弥
腹へってるっぽかったけど
What would she want to eat if
her stomach is giving her trouble?
おなかこわしてるのに
何が食べたいんだ？
ゾンビってことは…
If she's a zombie, that means...
Nah, couldn't be.
まさかな
Hey, w-who are you?!
ちょっと　だ…　誰？
あッ！　イタッ！
Ee-yow! What strength!
何？　この力…
Whoa!
ちょっと…　あッ
Aren't you...
あなたは…
...the Sanka girl?
散華家の…　うッ…
ちょっと！　いやあ…　うッ　いや…
Hold on!
No! H-Hold on, now!
ちょッ…　ちょっと…
Stop!
やめ…　うッ…
Hold on...!
ちょっと…
うッ…　もうッ！
えいッ
You're... really hurt, aren't you?!
あなた…　大けがしてるじゃない
W-What are you smiling about?!
な…　何　笑ってるのよ？
Have to hurry... and call an ambulance...
早く…　救急車
ウフフ…
Something's... not right...
＜何か…　変だよ
A-Are you telling me... she's...
まさか…　この子…
ウワ～ッ！
あッ？
あッ　わんこ…
Wanko? Don't tell me...
まさか！？
If I heard it coming from inside
the house, it couldn't mean...!
今　家の中から聞こえたってことは
まさか…
Ask before
coming in!!!
わんこ！　大丈夫…
Wanko!
Are you all... right?
Rea...? Your stiffness has already gone away?
礼弥　もう硬直が解けたのか？
Ch-Chihiro...
ち…　千紘
わんこ
Ranko... you're...
お前…
あッ…
Fu... Furuya...
ああ…　降谷君…
えッ…　何だよ？
W-What's going on?
ウワッ！
えッ？
うん　ハアッ…
えーッ！？
ばーぶ
Hitotsu dake kanau no nara
If I had just one wish
kimi no te no naka yureru chiisa na hana de itai
I would want to be a small flower, trembling in your hands
Hajimete miru mabushii kono sekai ga
Even if I become separated from you,
kimi to moshi hagureta to shite mo kitto
in this bright world I'm seeing for the first time,
mitsukedashite
I'm sure I'll find you
Mezametara soba ni iru yo
When I wake up, I'll stay beside you
ashita mo
tomorrow as well
Preview
A ratings stunt? What do you mean by that?
テコ入れ？
それは　どういうことかな？
If the mannerisms aren't working,
マンネリがまずいなら　言い方を
変えればよいのではないか？
we could always change the
delivery, couldn't we?
うん　まあ　仕方ない
Well, what choice is there?
You want to go with it this way, right?
この内容で　よいのだな？
Next time on Sankarea, episode 6:
"It's Because I... Ran Into You"
次回　「さんかれあ」　第６話
"It`s Because I... Ran Into You"
Do you all know the movie director,
萌路の名前のもとになった
ゾンビで有名な映画監督が
who is famous for zombies,
that my name is based on?
分かるかな？
正解は　みんな　ロメロで…
The answer is Romero!